Now let's see how bedrock agent core solves some of the challenges that we discussed previously.
We already discussed how the developer has written the agent aka application using
grieve AI on his local. Now the first thing he needs to do is, now he needs to deploy this
code on something known as agent core runtime. Now we can think of agent core runtime as an AWS
lambda for AI agents. So if you've used AWS lambda before, now you know that you can bring
your application code in any programming language and then deployed on AWS lambda and the underlying
infrastructure, the virtual machine, the micro VM or virtual machine would be managed by AWS.
So you can think of agent core runtime as very similar to AWS lambda for AI agents.
So now how do you deploy your agent code on this agent core runtime? To your existing code,
you add something known as agent core runtime decorator. So it's just a Python decorator and you can
see this is the application that we're going to build later and here I have in this crew.py file
and I have just added this decorator function and here we have this agent invocation and if you
see in the AWS lambda function, similarly we have the lambda handler function. So all you have to do
is add this decorator code and then you can deploy it on the agent core runtime and it will run
as a container. Okay. So now the good thing with agent core runtime is you can use any
agent API framework, whether it's line graph, crew a strands, all are supported by agent core
runtime and you can also have any large language model, whether it's from open AI, Gemini or Amazon
better. It will support all the elements and all the agentic frameworks. So what happens when you
deploy your agent decay code on the agent core runtime, it provides you with two endpoints.
So it converts it into an HTTP server and then provides you two endpoints. So it provides you an
invocation endpoint with post method and then it also provides you a ping endpoint for health checks.
So which essentially means that your end users can provide their inputs through this post endpoint
and they will go to get a response. So that's the first core capability which is agent core
runtime and we're going to deep dive into this a little later but for now it's just a high level
core. Okay. Now let's take a look at the second core capability of bedrock agent core.
Now once our agent decay code is hosted on the agent core runtime and we have the endpoints,
now we can have our end user and maybe we can make a request as you can see here planner,
itinerary for the London trip. So you can make that request to this endpoint and then our agent
will be able to process that. But before we can send this request, we need to look at the
authentication and authorization of this user. We need to make sure that this end user has
the right permissions to access this agent decay application and for that bedrock agent core provides
another capability called as agent core identity and it works at two levels. Inbound and outbound.
So what inbound does is it validates whether the person is actually the person who is claiming
to be and what are these authorization levels. So basically it looks at the authentication
and the authorization between the end user and the agentic AI application and for that it supports
any identity provider such as Amazon cognitive, entirety, octa and so on. So now let's say
our user has authenticated himself using Amazon cognitive and that the bearer token that cognitive
has generated is sent to the agent core, identity it does some validation and then if approved
it's able to send the request to this endpoint and access this agent decay application. So now
there are no more nuances when we go to the agent core identity service later we will be able to
understand that. Now the second component is the outbound and we will get to that in a little bit.
Now the third core capability of the agent core runtime is agent core memory. So it's a managed
service which provides memory at two levels. One is the short term memory so that is within
the session duration. So let's say our end user is interacting with applications and so you
interacts for 10 odd minutes, ask five 10 questions and then logs off. So as soon as the end user logs
off this short term memory will end but you have the option to keep the short term memory between
I think seven to 365 days but essentially it is only active during the duration of the session.
Next we have the long term memory and it provides multiple strategies so what you can do is
any interaction that you have today you can summarize that and store and next time you have
a having that conversation and it will use that summarized memory in the conversation. Then it
also provides semantic memory. So what semantic memory means is it will retain all the factual
information. Let's say you asked it about the address of a particular restaurant it will be
able to store that and then finally you have the user preferences. So let's say you prefer beaches
and next time you are looking for a dream destination it will give you more options related to
beaches. So you can select the long term memory strategy whether you want summarization, semantic or
user preferences. So next time you log in based on your strategy it's going to provide you the
contextual input. The next capability that we have is the agent core observability. It monitors
the agent performance in production and it does that through plot watch logs, matrix and now they
have provided another capability called as Gen AI observability which looks at the session trace
and span and we're going to deep dive into it a little later. So if we can show you quickly so I
am on the plot watch logs and here we have a new tab called as Gen AI observability which provide
a lot more details on agent matrix such as traces errors throttles and so on. Now finally we have
the agent core gateway agent core browser and agent core interpreter. These capabilities are focused on
how your agent can access various tools in a standardized format. Now let's try and understand
in more detail what these three services do. Now let's say our end user has finalized the London
as its dream destination and it wants to know what are the various travel packages that are offered
by this travel agency and for that this agent need to invoke an AWS Lambda tool which
retrieve some PDFs that are stored in the company S3 bucket or let's just assume that it needs
some details related to particular hotels which it can go ahead and fetch from SharePoint
and for that again you will have to write some tool which can access the data from SharePoint
and then provide it back to the agent. Now for these scenarios agent core gateway can help in
three ways. First it integrates with this agent core identity and here we can now look at this
outbound aspect. So what the outbound agent core identity does is it validates whether this tool
and this user actually has the permission to access those backend resources that are being retrieved
through these tools. So let's say if our travel package details are in a PDF in the S3 bucket
then does this user and this agent have does have the right permission to access those files.
Maybe if it's in the SharePoint more if it's more Microsoft based then does it have the right
API key to access that data. So it supports various permission level if it's an AWS service
then this agent needs the right. I am role if it's a Microsoft based solution then maybe you get
the enter ID token and that can be validated by this agent core gateway before it has access to
this SharePoint resource. So we'll get into details on how this actually works when we move to the
agent core section. So that's the first thing that agent core gateway does. The second thing
it helps is in discovery. Now let's say we have multiple agents here and let's say we have two dozen
tools. Now there's a request that has come from the user for access to a particular resource like
we're talking about the PDF in the S3 bucket. So what this agent core gateway will do is
out of those half a dozen tools that it will have based on the user query and it will automatically
do the tool discovery and then invoke the right tool. And then finally it also helps with MCP
modifying all the tools that you have as part of this agentic application. And if you don't know
what is MCP MCP refers to the model context protocol which is released by anthropic. So if you
don't know about what is MCP. I have added a refresher section towards the end of this course.
Please go ahead and take a look at that. Then we have the agent core browser. It works in a similar
fashion. Now let's say our end user likes our itinerary and it wants the address of a particular
location. So in that case what this agent can do is it can go and invoke this agent core browser
like humans do and it's going to retrieve the address of that particular location and provide it
back to the end user. And then finally we have the agent core interpreter maybe not relevant to this
use case. Now instead of this let's say you're building an application support agent which tries to
fix application code issues in the production. So in that scenario now let's say it has found and
fixed a bug and it wants to test out before applying that patch to the application. That's where
this agent core interpreter comes in handy. So you'll get a sandbox environment where you can
execute and test your code and if it works okay then you can go and finally apply the patch in the
production. Okay so those are some of the key bedrock agent capabilities. I hope you like this lecture
Thank you.